Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
Kyu,
would you stop by and see Grandpa
on your way home today?
Yeah. Sure thing.
Thank you.
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
Kyusho-kun! Your bag, your bag!
Here.
Thank You for Choosing Us
Kinme Cleaning
Thanks.
Wow, it's so clean now!
Come on, Kyu. Say thank you.
Thank you very much.
Not at all. Thank you very much
for choosing Kinme Cleaning.
Wash It
All Away
Episode 11   To Help This Little Guy Out
So the lead character wears glasses
and is super quiet so I thought,
hey, is that me?
He's lost it.
Huh? Kyu, am I loud?
Today, I want to talk to you
about inflected forms.
For example, the modern "omowanai"
turns into "omowazu,"
"omoimashita" becomes "omoikeri,"
"omou" becomes "omofu," and "omou toki"...
Whoa.
He's fast.
Yo, Kyu.
You really should join the track club.
It's already... second year...
Probably too late.
Nah, it would be fine.
Seriously, give it some thought. We don't
have a middle-distance runner right now.
Yeah, but...
I still have to help at home.
I figured you'd say something like that.
Maybe I'll just have to run.
Okay, see ya later!
Yeah!
Kyu-kun, why are you so
spaced out recently? Not sleeping?
Kyu's always out of orbit somewhere.
Right?
But you gotta get enough sleep, man.
Yeah, I wonder.
Mm-hmm.
I'm asleep five seconds
after I hit the pillow!
Listen up. It's normal to want to find
the easiest way to solve a math equation,
but once you realize
there's this other method,
things start to get interesting.
All right, so let's see you use this
formula to determine the value.
Sato-san?
I'm so sorry!
Um, would you mind if we slept
in the same room tonight?
I'm sorry. Did I wake you?
Just now in the bath,
I started wondering about what could
have caused me to be so afraid of thunder.
Okay, that's about all
we have time for today.
Be sure to review this at home, everyone.
Man, I didn't catch a single word in math.
Ishimochi? Wakasagi?
Huh?
Are you boys getting enough rest?
You're sleeping in class a lot recently.
Ah, whoops.
Yeah, sorry.
Oh boy. Try to stay awake.
Oh, that's so clean!
A clean bag says a lot about a person.
Thank you.
On the other hand...
Oops.
Wakasagi, your bag looks like trash.
Yeah. I was actually planning
to wash it this week.
Huh? Aren't you getting off, Kyu-kun?
What?
Oh. Sorry.
I gotta go see my grandpa.
Gotcha.
See ya.
Yeah. See you tomorrow.
The doors of the train on track two
are closing. Please stand clear.
Suzuki
Family Grave
Aoki
Nakata
Family Grave
Aoki
Ishimochi Family
I might as well go up
to the top while I'm here.
Izukai Shrine
The climb is always a pain, though.
At least it's easier now
than when I was a kid.
Oh, what?
Kinme-san? What are you doing here?
What are you doing here, Kyusho-kun?
Well, I did some cleaning and I thought
I'd visit the shrine while I'm at it.
Cleaning?
Um, my grandpa's grave is down below.
Oh, so you were cleaning the grave.
Mom usually takes care of it,
but she asked me to come today.
Is that so?
It's so responsible of you
to pay respect to your ancestors.
Yeah, but it's no exaggeration to say
I wouldn't be here without
my grandpa and family.
That's such a nice way to see it.
Kyusho-kun, that's one reason
I think I like you so much.
Um, Kinme-san, I...
Hmm?
I've been wondering
about something, and...
Huh? What? Kyusho-kun?
Wash It All Away
Unfortunately, I am a little
backed up at the moment,
so I'm afraid it will take
one day longer than usual.
Is that still all right with you?
Yes, that's fine.
Thank you very much.
As always, you can count on Kinme!
I'll see you then.
All right!
Hello, Kinme-oneesan!
Oh, hello. Come on in.
Hello. Looks like you're keeping busy.
Yes, I sure am.
Refresher
Busy Seasons
for Cleaners
April-June
(Putting Away
Winter Clothes)
September-October
(Putting Away
Summer Clothes)
End & Beginning of Year
(Yearly Cleaning)
We do get a lot of business
around this time of year.
Here Now
Well, I'm sorry to bother you, then,
but may I still ask you
to clean these for me?
Oh, of course! Thank you very much.
There.
Are you taking more pictures
for social media?
Yes!
Mother, I'd like to take some more
pictures before I go home.
Oh my.
Is that all right?
It's such a busy time for you.
I will not get in her way one bit!
Yes, it's fine with me.
I see. Well, thank you very much.
Nairo, do not cause her
any trouble at all.
Okay!
Don't you think we've taken
enough of this kind of picture?
Oh, definitely not!
We need newer pictures of you working
to keep appearing on the timeline!
I guess that's how it works.
Yes! But videos actually get
more attention than pictures do.
See, like this one.
The number of views is... Ten thousand?!
10,126 Views
Here is Kinme-san, the owner of Kinme Cleaning, treating a
stain on a customer's garment! She works very carefully,
applying a series of detergents to safely remove the stain.
Yes. I'm the same way,
but everyone seems to be really interested
in your stain-removing steam sprayer!
So I would love to take another video
of you removing stains today.
Hmm. But I've already pretty much
finished stain treatment for the day.
Oh? What is that over there?
There's a square on the floor.
Huh? A square?
Oh, you mean that.
Is it some kind of door?
Yes, probably.
You mean you've never opened it?
No. I tried to open it once
soon after I started here,
but the handle was stuck, so I gave up.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, wow!
Nairo-chan?
Um, um, let's open it right now!
We might make a great discovery!
Let's get some torches ready!
Huh? Torches?
Last time, I wasn't able to open it
by pulling on the handle.
So maybe if I try this...
Oh.
It's open!
Sigh.
Wow, so it just comes right off.
I figured it was underfloor storage space.
My castle...
I wonder if these belong to the owner
of the previous cleaning shop.
Everything looks very worn out and rusty.
Yes, it does.
What could that be?
Find something?
A stuffed animal?
There's a hole torn in the bag,
so it's grown filthy.
There's a receipt!
Which means this must be an item that
a customer brought in to be cleaned.
Looks like it is very moldy
and discolored.
I feel kind of bad for it.
Underfloor spaces are humid
and have poor air circulation,
so they aren't really suitable
for storing things made of fabric.
So why keep a customer's
precious stuffed animal there?
Aji-san did tell me that this building
was used for another cleaning shop
Welcome!
2x Points
Every Tuesday
long before I moved in.
If that previous manager
is responsible for this,
as a cleaner myself, I do not approve.
What's wrong?
You look upset about something.
Huh? Oh, nothing.
But I should try to contact the owner.
Hmm. I can't get through
to the number on the receipt.
There is an address, though...
Um, so what do you plan
to do with the stuffed animal?
Good question.
Collection Receipt
Location:
Name: Mutsu-sama
Date Received: June 4
Scheduled Pick-up Date: June 25
Please bring this receipt when you come to pick up your item.
We cannot be held responsible for items that are not claimed within one month.
Item: Stuffed Animal
If this was meant for
the previous shop to clean,
it might seem a bit presumptuous
for me to do something.
Then again, I can't just leave
something so dirty in this state.
I am going to wash it.
I'm also doing it to help this
little guy out, after being trapped
alone in the dark for so long.
Wow.
Can you explain what
you're doing right now?
I'm press-washing it.
Stuffed animals are filled with padding,
so I put a small amount of mildly acidic
commercial detergent in warm water
and press it gently to wash the insides.
Wow! It's like the little guy
is taking a bath!
After press-washing, I rinse it
two or three times the same way.
It isn't always clear what plush toys
like this are stuffed with,
so it is best not to soak them completely
unless absolutely necessary.
Also, if you aren't careful to
dry them completely afterwards,
they can easily become
a breeding ground for mold.
And then, and then,
what do you do after that?
I dry it.
You're going to spin it around?
If you spin it too hard, the stuffing
could get bunched up
and change the shape of the toy,
so I keep a close eye on the time
and temperature and just dry it partway.
Huh? Didn't you say you needed
to dry it completely?
Yes, so after this, I'll take him
to the back yard to relax.
Huh?
It's a flat drying net.
I hang it in the shade
until it dries and then I'm done.
This is going to be a popular post!
Nairo-chan, would you mind
not posting this quite yet?
Huh?
Welcome
Open
Business Hours From 2 p.m. to 9 p.m.
Hot Spring Bath
Atami Station Front
Station Front
Hot Spring
Where did it come from?
Aji-san!
Hmm?
Someone from the moving company
might have stuffed it under the floor.
Moving company?
When the last cleaner closed shop,
I left everything to a moving company.
I had them clean everything and even
sort through all the equipment.
Those bums had the nerve to tell me there
wasn't anything in the underfloor storage.
I see.
What a mess. I should have
checked it myself to be sure.
Well, I never bothered
to look inside until now either.
But I don't have any idea who
brought that stuffed animal in.
It's really far up the hill, isn't it?
Yes.
We can see the ocean in the distance!
Wow, we really can!
Is it around here?
Hmm. It should be.
Do you think they remember
bringing the stuffed animal in?
I certainly hope they do.
Let's see...
I think this is it.
Oh no! There isn't even a house here!
K-Kinme-oneesan, what should we do?
Should we go ahead and post about it?
You know, it could've been a family
with a vacation home here.
Vacation home?
Then they might have stopped visiting
here and forgot to go pick it up.
That could happen.
If that's the case, what should I do?
There's really nothing to do.
Do whatever feels right to you.
Everything happens for a reason.
Kinme-oneesan?
I think I'll take it back to the shop
and take care of it for a while.
Huh?
Especially since it's all clean now.
Does this look all right?
Yes!
Do you recognize me?
Does anyone out there recognize me?
I've found a stuffed animal that was left by the previous cleaners.
The family at the address that was left have moved away,
so I haven't been able to return him to his owner.
I hope his owners find him.
Translation:
Editing and Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Episode 12  Local Cleaning with a Heart
Next time, "Local Cleaning with a Heart."